hey guys this is one of the most
requested videos I've ever had and for
good reason this is such a cool problem
I did not expect it to have the outcome
that it had so the problem gives us a
semicircle right here and a quarter
Circle right here and then this red line
with a length of five that goes from the
vertex of this rectangle tangent to the
semicircle if you want to try this on
your own pause it right now cuz I'm
going to solve it in 3 2 1 so first up
let's assign a radius to this semi
circle a lot of people wanted to assign
this radius to match but there really is
not evidence that this radius is the
same as this radius so let's call it
something else like X using our method
we're not going to need this radius to
equal this radius and that right there
is one of my favorite things about this
problem we don't care if the radi are
the same so this last distance right
here will also be R because it's a
radius of the same semicircle and this
height will also be X because it's a
radius of this quarter Circle and now we
can come up with a formula for the area
of the rectangle the area of a rectangle
is base time height the base is going to
be equal to x + 2 R and the height is
going to be